Finding Aid for the Edwin Sheffield Gleaves Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- PUBLICATIONS AND REPORTS, 1967-1984
  - Northern Illinois University -- Lecture on Latin America Librarianship, April 1, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Peabody Journal of Education -- Special Issue (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - “The Nashville Union Catalog: A Report.” (ESG and Margareta Martin) (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - “No Tears For Absalom” (ESG) (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Paraguay -- Article on National Library (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Paraguay -- Informe Sobre El Proyecto De La Escuela De Bllbliotecologia, UNA (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - “The Peabody Education Library: Future Imperfect Tense” (ESG) (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - “Peabody Perspectives in Library Science” -- An Experiment in Continuing Education (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - People-to-People Librarians (ESG) (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - The Placement Picture, 1973: A Peabody Perspective (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Possibilities with Paperbacks in Libraries; A Bibliographical Checklist of Suggestions (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Profile of A Library School (ESG) (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Puerto Rico -- “Escuela Graduada de Bibliotecologia” (ESG) (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Report of A Planning Conference for Solar Technology Information Transfer (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - The Role of TLA in Continuing Education: Time to Come Clean” (ESG) (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Salpicando: Mexico Supplement 1 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Salpicando: Costa Rica -- A Journal of Random Observations (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Salpicando: Mexico (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Salpicando: Some Notes from Paraguay (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Salpicando: Some Notes from Paraguay (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - “Seattle and the University Washington” (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Serving Yesterday’s People Tomorrow: Bookmobile Programs and Reading Interests in Rural Tennessee (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - SELA, 1976 -- Microforms Workshop (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Report on Fort Loudon Reg.Lib.Ctr. (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Report on Tennessee Regional Library for the Blind and Physically Handicapped (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Report on Memphis Area Resource Center (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Report on Nashville Area Resource Center (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Library of the Tennessee State Penitentiary: An Evaluation Report for the T. A. C. L. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Report on Caney Fork Reg. Lib. Ctr. (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Report on WPIN Talking Library (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Reports on Area Resource Centers, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Tennessee Regional Library System -- Tenn. Regional Library for the Blind and Physically Handicapped (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Tennessee Regional Library System -- Warioto Regional Library (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Three Agenda for Research in Library and Information Science” (ESG) (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Tennessee Advisory Council on Libraries Reports on Warioto Regional Library (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - “Los Territorios Academicos... “ Revista Interamericana de Bibliotecologia (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - TLA -- Committee on Pornography Bill (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - United Methodist Publishing House Final Report (Original) (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - “A Watch and Chain and a Jeweled Sword” Drafts, Correspondence, etc. (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - “A Watch and Chain and a Jeweled Sword” as submitted to RQ, (13 August 1984) (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - A Watch and Chain and a Jeweled Sword or the Graveyard of Scholarship: Festschrift and Librarianship (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Wisconsin, University of, Oshkosh -- Consultant Visit on ALA Accreditation (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Webster’s New World Dictionary (ESG) Type Script (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Young Harris College (Box 14, Folder 58)
- LATIN AMERICA
  - Columbia (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Costa Rica (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Escuela Interamericana de Bibliotecologia (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - EIBM -- History, etc. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Mexico -- San LUIS Potosi, etc. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Mexico -- “Project Mexico-Peabody: A Proposal for a Short-Term Seminar in Nashville” (ESG) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Mexico -- Conacyt (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Mexico -- Reunion Sobre Grandes Cencentracions Universitaraias (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Mexico -- University of Guanajuato, 1985-86, -- Thesis (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Passport and Travel Information (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Organization of American States, Correspondence, Contracts, etc, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Paraguay -- Universidad nacional de Asuncion, Escuela de Bibliotecologia (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Unesco (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Unesco -- Simposio, Interamanicano San Jose, Costa Rica, Feb. 1981 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Venezuela -- Sinasbi (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Venezuela -- ULA -- Course on Microforms, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Venezuela -- Proyecto de Adquisicion Cooperativa (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Venezuela -- U. D. O. -- Course on Microforms (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Venezuela -- L. U. Z. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Venezuela -- U. L. A. -- Mf Workshop -- Class List (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Venezuela -- Universidad de los Andes (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Venezuela (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Venezuela -- U. L. A. -- Projectos de Clase (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Venezuela -- U. C. V. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Venezuela -- Consejo Nacional de Uuniversidad Comiscion de Trabejo -- Projecto de Plan (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Venezuela -- Don Quixote de la Mancha: Comparative Translations (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - “Readers Indigestion”, Post Article (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Language -- Dialects (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Language -- Ideographs (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Language -- Development of the Alphabet (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Language -- Names (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - English Literature -- The Victorian Age -- English 516b (GPL) (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - English Literature -- The Victorian Poetry and Prose -- English 258 (GPL) (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Libraries Unlimited (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Southwestern Publishing Co. (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Mercy College (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Kentucky, University of, -- Personal Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Metodos de Ensenanza –Universidad de Costa Rica, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - EIB Seleccion de Material –Photocopies of Articles (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - EB-316 Seleccion de Material (Part 1) Universidad de Costa Rica, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - EB-316 El Lector y la Biblioteca (Part 2) Unversidad de Costa Rica, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 42)
- PUBLICATIONS AND REPORTS, 1967 (A-MEX)
  - All in One Boat: The Case for Educating for the Global View TVA Presentation, March 24, 83 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - ALA -- IRRT -- Special Issue of LEADS, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - “ALA and Library Education for the 1970s” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The Bibliosmiles (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Building Library Collections (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Careers of Diversity in an Age of Adversity: Librarianship, Information Science and Information Management (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Creacion de un Ambiente Efectivo Papa Microformas en Bibliotecas: un Modulo Instructivo (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Creating an Effective Microform Environment in Libraries: a Self-Instructional Learning Module (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Creating an Effective Microform Environment in Libraries, Original, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Creating an Effective Microform Environment in Libraries: a Self-Instructional Learning Module (Original) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Creating an Effective Microform Environment in Libraries: a Self-Instructional Learning Module (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Creating an Effective Microform Environment in Libraries: a Self-Instructional Learning Module (revised edition) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - “Current Sources of Statistics on Library Education” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Department of Library and Information Science (Contribution to McCrossan Volume) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - “Drury, F. K. W. “, Dictionary of American Library Biography (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - “La Escuela Interammericana de Bibliotecologia: A Report with Recommendations” (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - “La Escuela Interammericana de Bibliotecologia: A Report with Recommendations” (ESG)” (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - “Evaluation of the Library School Directory” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - “Faculty Teaching Loads In Graduate Schools in the Southeast” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - “The Fisk University Library Research Program in Ethnic Studies Librarianship: An Evaluation Report” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - “Focus On... the IRRT of the ALA” Information Development (1-86) (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - “Formacion de Personal Bibliotecario en la Era Electronica” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - “George Peabody College, School of Library Science,” Encyclopedia of Library and Information Science (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - “Graduate Courses in Library Science Offered in the Southeast During the 1978 and 1979 Summer Sessions” (RTC & ESG) (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - History of Library Education (ESG & JMT) (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - IFIA Preconference,, Montreal, August 1982 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - “Information Requirements of University Faculty” (ERIC) (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - “Innocents Abroad: Americans Among Other Cultures”. CIEC Speech, March 25, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - “International Relations Round Table”. ALA Yearbook, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - “Intellectual Freedom in Tennessee”. Tres Pasos Adelante (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - “Intellectual Freedom in Tennessee”, (ESG), L.S. 221, Spring, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - “La Investigation en las Escuelas de Bibliotecologia... “ (ESG & RH) - Original (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - “La Investigation en las Escuelas de Bibliotecologia... “ (ESG & RH) -Support Materials (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - “Jonathan Livingston Librarian” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Lambuth College (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Letters to Newspapers (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Library Education in Transition (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - “Library Instruction in the Library School Curriculum” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Library Education: Issues for the Eighties (Top Copy) (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - “The Literary Catabomb” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - “A Literary Catacomb” (Popular Literature) (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - “Library Education: Issues for the Eighties” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Reference Services Review. The Literary Elite: A Personal Selection of the Most Essential Titles... (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Literary Manslaughter (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - “The Literary Catacomb” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - “Looking Backward, Learning Forward: or From Ragtime to Tymshare” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - “Marietta and the Virgin and I” (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - La Maestria en Bibliotecologia Y Ciencias de la Informmacion de la Universidad de Guanajuato (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Mexico -- “Un Problema Bibliotecario Inesperado” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Mexico -- “Curso de Orientacion en Bibliotecologia en Mexico” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Mexico -- “Analysis of ‘Estudios Propuestos Para un Programa de Maestria en Bibliotecologia’... ” (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - Mexico -- “San Luis Potosi Como Sede Del Curso De Maestria En Bibliotecologia” (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Questionnaire: Information Requirements of University Faculty: An Investigation into the Information Needs, Habits, and Attitudes of the faculty of George Peabody College for Teachers of Vanderbilt University, 1984 (ESG) (Box 16, Folder 54)